hi and welcome back to Polar Ice
Creamery and today we are going to start
our series on sugars the different types
of sugar that you're using ice cream and
how they will affect your
recipe so a lot of you have been asking
for me to do some videos on this subject
and sugars is quite a broad subject so
we're going to do lots of short little
episodes for this series and obviously
the first and most obvious one to start
with is is sucrose sucrose is standard
table sugar if you were to go into any
store and buy a bag of sugar that is
what you're buying sucrose it's a
naturally occurring sugar found in
various plants fruits vegetables nuts
Etc it is also commercially produced
from sugar cane and sugar beets and in
its basic standard form sucrose has 4
calories per gram so all all sugar has a
really important role in your ice cream
it adds the sweetness required but also
deals with freezing point depression
without any sugar at all in your ice
cream you're going to suffer with two
major problems one is it just won't have
enough solids so it be very watery and
two freezing point depression so it will
be solid as a rock so when you combine
those two things you're going to have
watery ice cream with with no internal
solids you're going to end up with a
frozen mess that just won't taste very
good in a standard homemade ice cream
recipe sucros can account for usually
does account for 100% of the added sugar
that excludes the lactose which is also
sugar naturally found in the dairy
historically American style ice cream so
a hard churned ice cream has anywhere
between 13 and
20% sugar content gelato on the other
hand has anywhere from 15 to
23% sugar content then your sherbets and
loafer ice creams generally have much
higher sugar content ordinarily to deal
with the lack of solids and other
essential ingredients that they use in a
basic form if you're making homemade ice
cream if it's a little bit too hard when
you take it out of freezer the most
simple way to rectify that is to add a
little bit more sugar and that will make
it a little bit softer that will
increase the freezing point depression
of your ice cream as a side note the
more sugar you add into your ice cream
the less of the flavor is going to come
through so not only will the dairy dull
the flavor the sugar will dull the
flavor
too in the world of ice cream we have
acronyms we have pod and pack P Pac
these two things are your Baseline
sweetness
or relative sweetness as it's commonly
known and the freezing point depression
number sucros being the most common type
of sugar starts off the whole variation
for these numbers with a level of 100 so
that's your Baseline figure Su has 100
pod 100 pack we will talk more about the
Pod and pack numbers as we go through
this sugar series there's a lot to learn
with regards to Sugar so I will cover
this in various different episodes well
that's it a nice easy start to the sugar
series suit Crow it's the sugar that
pretty much everyone uses not just for
ice cream just for everything and you
can make really really top-notch ice
cream just by using suit cross you don't
need to add all the other ones but when
you get into the scientific side of ice
cream creation that's when these other
sugars are going to come into play so
next time we're going to talk about
dexos which is another really common
sugar also called corn sugar in certain
parts of the world so if you're
interested in that one don't forget to
like And subscribe and I will see you
next
[Music]
time